Episode 17
에피소드 17
Brother Juqing.
주칭 형제.
I embroidered this myself.
이건 제가 직접 수놓은 거예요.
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
Your Highness is no longer interested in me.
전하는 더 이상 나에게 관심이 없습니다.
Sooner or later she will allow me to leave.
조만간 그녀는 내가 떠나도록 허락할 것이다.
My father arranged a marriage for me.
아버지는 나를 위해 결혼을 주선해 주셨습니다.
Please continue.
계속 진행하시기 바랍니다.
And I wish you wealth
그리고 나는 당신에게 부를 기원합니다
And happiness.
그리고 행복.
you...
너...
Are you getting married?
결혼해요?
Yes, next month.
네, 다음 달이에요.
When you asked me to take you with me
나를 데려가 달라고 했을 때
You said you didn't want to leave your family.
당신은 가족을 떠나고 싶지 않다고 말했어요
And I was afraid.
그리고 두려워했습니다.
And now you have come to rub salt in my wounds.
그리고 이제 당신은 내 상처에 소금을 바르러 왔습니다.
Nickname...
주칭...
Why did I fall in love with someone like you?
나는 왜 당신 같은 사람을 사랑하게 됐나요?
Forget it.
잊어 버려.
I misjudged you.
나는 당신을 잘못 판단했습니다.
I wasn't lucky to have met you.
나는 당신을 만난 것이 운이 좋지 않았습니다.
You are in charge of delivery.
배송 담당이시네요
This time with Hwangcheong.
이번에는 황청으로.
Is it true?
사실인가요?
yes
예
But the purpose you are going for is
하지만 네가 가는 목적은
Ruxin is making you completely forget about him.
Ruxin이 당신을 완전히 잊게 만드는 것입니다.
She is no longer young.
그녀는 더 이상 젊지 않습니다.
One of her maids sent me a message.
그녀의 하녀 중 한 명이 나에게 메시지를 보냈습니다.
Saying that he still has feelings for you
그 사람이 아직 너에 대한 감정을 갖고 있다고 말하면서
After all these years.
이 세월이 흐른 뒤에야.
this time
이 시간
you will go
너는 갈 것이다
And make her forget about you completely.
그리고 그녀가 당신을 완전히 잊게 만드세요.
What if I don't want to do it?
내가 그 일을 하고 싶지 않으면 어떻게 하나요?
Then you will never see her again.
그러면 당신은 그녀를 다시는 볼 수 없을 것입니다.
Do not forget it
잊지 마세요
you and your family
당신과 당신의 가족
You are my slave.
내 노예야.
Think of her.
그녀를 생각해보세요.
Between the servant's sons
종의 아들 사이
And the lord of the Zong family
그리고 종 가문의 영주
In Hwangcheong
황청에서는
Who is the better choice?
누가 더 나은 선택인가?
It's clear.
분명합니다.
do as i say
내가 말한대로 해
Then I will return your contract to you
그러면 나는 당신의 계약을 당신에게 돌려줄 것입니다
So you and your family will be free.
그래서 당신과 당신의 가족은 자유로울 것입니다.
But if you insist on not doing that
하지만 그렇게 하지 않겠다고 고집한다면
Ruxin is never seen again.
Ruxin을 다시는 볼 수 없습니다.
You can take this chance
이 기회를 잡아도 돼
To say goodbye to her.
그녀에게 작별 인사를 하기 위해.
shake it
흔들어
I sincerely hope
진심으로 바랍니다
you will buy
당신은 살 것이다
A life of wealth and glory.
부와 영광의 삶.
to let go...
놓치다...
Lady, calm down.
아가씨, 진정하세요.
I agreed to come to the Bell Garden
나는 종의 정원에 오기로 동의했습니다
Because I didn't want my father to punish him.
왜냐하면 나는 아버지가 그를 처벌하는 것을 원하지 않았기 때문입니다.
???Ass... ???But what did I get?
???아스... ???그런데 내가 뭘 얻었나요?
???Miss... ???What did I get?
???미스... ???내가 뭘 얻었나요?
to let go.
놓치다.
Sir, Qin Lin is your servant.
선생님, 진린은 하인입니다.
There is a better choice.
더 나은 선택이 있습니다.
I'm sure your father did the right thing.
나는 당신 아버지가 옳은 일을 했다고 확신해요.
A better choice?
더 나은 선택?
What other options do I have?
나에게 또 어떤 선택이 있나요?
I suffered for so long
너무 오랫동안 고생했어요
And I got this result.
그리고 이런 결과를 얻었습니다.
???Tell me please. ???me...
???말해 주세요. ???나...
Why am I the only one who feels miserable?
왜 나만 비참하다고 느끼는 걸까?
Calm down, girl...
진정하세요, 아가씨...
love is the most worthless thing
사랑은 가장 가치없는 일이다
oh my god.
세상에.
'Cause nothing goes right for me
나한테는 아무 일도 제대로 되지 않으니까
I will make others feel what I feel.
나는 내가 느끼는 것을 나머지 사람들도 느끼게 해줄 것이다.
Please take a seat, Second Aunt.
자리에 앉으세요, 둘째 이모님.
Did your second aunt come alone?
둘째이모님 혼자 오셨나요?
yes.
예.
We haven't seen each other for a long time
우리는 오랫동안 서로를 보지 못했어요
And I heard you missed us
그리고 네가 우리를 그리워했다고 들었어
So I came right here.
그래서 바로 여기로 왔어요.
The bell garden is wonderful.
종의 정원은 훌륭합니다.
The quality of everything here is much better
여기 있는 모든 것의 품질이 훨씬 더 좋습니다
Than your uncle uses
네 삼촌이 사용하는 것보다
I thank Her Highness for her care.
나는 그녀의 보살핌에 대해 그녀의 전하에게 감사드립니다.
Your mother praised your brother
네 어머니가 네 동생을 칭찬하셨지
Because she was wise when she was in the city.
그녀가 도시에 있을 때 현명했기 때문입니다.
I think you are much wiser.
내 생각에는 당신이 훨씬 더 현명하다고 생각해요
Than her.
그녀보다.
She lives with my sister.
그녀는 내 여동생과 함께 산다.
What she thinks is right.
그녀가 생각하는 것이 옳다
My younger sister is more likable.
내 여동생이 더 호감이 간다.
you're welcome.
별말씀을요.
How does your sister compare to you?
당신의 여동생은 당신과 어떻게 비교될 수 ​​있나요?
You have spent a lot of time with His Highness.
당신은 전하와 함께 많은 시간을 보냈습니다.
very likely
그럴 가능성이 매우 높다
You will be a member of the Jong family...
당신은 종 가족의 사람이 될 것입니다 ...
Anyway, my family
아무튼 우리 가족은
It will be up to you.
당신에게 달려있을 것입니다.
How are my cousins ​​and uncles?
내 사촌과 삼촌은 잘 지내요?
I haven't seen them for a while
한동안 그들을 보지 못했어요
And I miss them a little bit.
그리고 나는 그들이 조금 그리워요.
are you okay. let me tell them
괜찮아요. 내가 그들에게 말해줄게
I'm coming to see you.
당신을 만나러 오려고요.
That's a really good idea.
정말 좋은 생각이야.
I have something to ask my uncle.
삼촌한테 물어볼 게 있어요.
As expected, my father contacts me often.
역시 아버지는 자주 연락을 하신다.
Through him and letters.
그와 편지를 통해.
It's true.
그것은 사실이다.
Have some tea, second aunt.
차 좀 드세요, 둘째 이모님.
OK.
괜찮은.
How have you been?
어떻게 지냈어?
can you tell?
당신은 말할 수 있습니까?
What scent is it today?
오늘은 무슨 향이야?
It looks a little familiar to me
나한테는 좀 낯익은데
But I can’t put my finger on it.
하지만 손가락을 댈 수가 없어요.
Mother, be careful.
어머니, 조심하세요.
It's a Chuseok scent.
추석 향입니다.
???Butler Whoa. ???You really are a deacon.
???버틀러 후아. ???정말 집사님이시군요.
I could tell even from afar.
멀리서도 알 수 있었습니다.
Come, baby.
오세요, 자기야.
Mom, I will sit over there.
어머니, 저는 저쪽에 앉을게요.
???long time no see. ???of course.
???오랜만이네요. ???물론.
How is your business?
당신의 사업은 어떻습니까?
???What happen? ???Please give it here.
???무슨 일이에요? ???여기로 주세요.
Let’s eat and be healthy, okay?
밥 먹고 건강해지자, 알았지?
Is he going to eat more?
그 사람은 더 먹을 건가요?
I can't even pass through this wide passage.
이 넓은 통로도 통과할 수 없어요.
Doesn't he know how fat he is?
그 사람은 자기가 얼마나 뚱뚱한지 모르나요?
Quiet. Isn't he your son?
조용히 해. 그 사람 당신 아들 아닌가요?
OK.
괜찮은.
Chuseok incense is very expensive.
추석 향은 매우 비쌉니다.
Ordinary deacons like us can't afford that at all.
우리 같은 일반 집사들은 전혀 그럴 여유가 없습니다.
I can only smell it from here.
여기서만 냄새를 맡을 수 있어요.
No wonder I didn't realize it.
내가 그것을 인식하지 못한 것도 당연합니다.
yes. Hua Residence has a lot to offer.
예. Hua Residence에는 많은 것이 있어야합니다.
So he was able to identify it.
그래서 그는 그것을 식별할 수 있었습니다.
That's why people say this.
그렇기 때문에 사람들은 이렇게 말합니다.
The Hua family is the second
Hua 가족은 두 번째입니다
Brings wealth to the Zhong family.
Zhong 가족에게 부를 가져다줍니다.
There are also paintings and calligraphy.
그림과 캘리그라피도 있어요.
Could you rate it?
평가해 주시겠어요?
I'm sure...
확신하는...
Hello everyone.
여러분, 안녕하세요.
long time no see.
오랜만이에요.
father. mother.
아버지. 어머니.
Kian...
키안...
come...
오다...
Kian.
키안.
Princess Royal has arrived.
프린세스 로얄이 도착했습니다.
Hello, Lord, Your Majesty.
안녕하세요, 주님, 전하.
Everyone please take your seats.
모두들 자리에 앉으세요.
Thank you, God.
신 이여, 감사합니다.
I hope everyone has a happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
모두들 행복한 중추절 보내시기 바랍니다.
Thank you for your hard work last year.
지난 한해 수고 많으셨습니다.
Let me propose a toast.
건배를 제안하겠습니다.
Make yourself at home.
집처럼 편안하게 지내세요.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
감사합니다, 전하.
???Please, teacher. ???I will help you.
???부디 선생님. ???내가 도와 줄게.
Qian, why are you sitting here?
Qian, 왜 여기 앉아 있나요?
eat your food
네 음식을 먹어.
I just want to talk to you.
나는 단지 당신과 이야기하고 싶습니다.
I haven't seen you for a month.
나는 당신을 한 달 동안 보지 못했습니다.
I think I lost weight again.
또 살이 빠진 것 같아요.
Let's talk after the banquet is over.
연회가 끝난 후에 이야기하자.
last time you were in my room
지난번에 네가 내 방에 있었을 때
You said you would come see me
나를 만나러 온다고 했잖아
But you didn't.
하지만 당신은 그러지 않았어요.
Thank you for your courage in raising this issue.
이 문제를 제기하는 당신의 용기.
Think about what you have done.
당신이 무엇을 했는지 생각해 보세요.
And cause me less trouble
그리고 나에게 문제를 덜 일으키게 해
You don't need to worry that much.
그렇게 걱정할 필요는 없어요.
III didn't spoil anything this time.
III는 이번에는 아무것도 망치지 않았습니다.
what? Isn’t that how it should be?
무엇? 원래 그래야 하는 것 아닌가요?
Do you want me to compliment you?
내가 당신을 칭찬해주기를 바라나요?
One more word and I'll be done.
한 마디만 더 하면 이만 마치겠습니다.
OK.
괜찮은.
Qian, we are at a banquet.
Qian, 우리는 연회 중이에요.
Could you be kinder to that person?
그 사람에게 좀 더 친절하게 대할 수 있나요?
A month has passed
한 달이 지났어요
I'm still waiting for my father's reply.
저는 아직도 아버지의 답장을 기다리고 있습니다.
So now I want to ask you directly.
그래서 이제 직접 여러분께 묻고 싶습니다.
Have you decided, Father?
결정하셨나요, 신부님?
It wasn't easy for us
우리에겐 쉽지 않았어
To get to where we are today.
오늘 우리가 있는 곳에 도달하기 위해.
Please don't mention this again.
이 문제를 다시 언급하지 마세요.
OK. I understand.
괜찮은. 나는 이해했다.
Father, I did my best.
아버지, 저는 최선을 다했습니다.
Qian, I worry too much.
퀴안, 걱정이 너무 많아.
Why don't you go home?
집에 가지 않을래?
And how many days off?
그리고 며칠 쉬어?
It doesn't have to be that way.
그럴 필요는 없습니다.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Kian!
키안!
Who was she mad at?
그녀는 누구에게서 화를 냈습니까?
Are you leaving, Mr. Hua?
떠날 건가요, Hua 선생님?
Lord.
주님.
A divorce letter is sent
이혼편지가 발송됩니다
Later to your residence.
나중에 당신의 거주지로.
???Divorce letter? ???yes.
???이혼편지? ???예.
It has my stamp on it.
내 도장이 찍혀있어요
Only then can you see the effect.
그래야 효과를 볼 수 있다
Without signing your name.
당신의 이름에 서명하지 않고.
Thank you, God.
신 이여, 감사합니다.
I will go back and wait.
나는 돌아가서 기다릴 것이다.
Hua Chen...
화첸...
Lord, we are in the garden of servants.
주님, 우리는 종의 정원에 있습니다.
Many people pass through this place.
많은 사람들이 이곳을 거쳐가고 있습니다.
No one knows about divorce yet.
아직 이혼에 대해 아는 사람은 아무도 없습니다.
I don't want rumors to spread.
소문이 퍼지는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
This will also ruin your reputation.
그러면 당신의 평판도 망가질 것입니다.
Who is he?
그는 누구입니까?
He is Hua Rongzhou.
그는 화룽저우(Hua Rongzhou)이다.
A guard at the servant's residence.
종 거주지의 경비원.
He is like a block of wood.
그는 나무 블록과 같습니다.
He made you angry because he was worried.
그 사람은 걱정해서 당신을 화나게 했어요
For my reputation.
내 평판을 위해.
Is your last name angry?
성이 화예요?
we share the same last name
우리는 같은 성을 공유해요
But we are not related.
하지만 우리는 관련이 없습니다.
My father told me not to go too far.
아버지는 너무 멀리 가지 말라고 하셨습니다.
Lord, I'd better go back.
주님, 돌아가는 것이 좋겠습니다.
Does that person look familiar to you?
그 사람이 당신에게 친숙해 보이나요?
He is the mistress's personal guard.
그는 여주인의 개인 경비원입니다.
I've seen him several times before.
나는 이전에 그를 여러 번 본 적이 있습니다.
I think I saw him from very far away.
내 생각엔 그 사람을 아주 멀리서 본 것 같아.
Call Lin Jiang to confirm his identity.
Lin Jiang을 불러 그의 신원을 확인하세요.
Yes, Lord.
네, 주님.
I know you are old
나는 당신이 나이가 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다
If you stand up quickly for justice
정의를 위해 신속하게 일어서면
But you need to consider who you are dealing with.
하지만 당신은 당신이 누구를 상대하고 있는지 고려해야 합니다.
If you insult the Lord
만일 당신이 주님을 모욕한다면
I may not be able to save you either.
나도 당신을 구하지 못할 수도 있습니다.
The hostess, Guard Hua, said that.
여주인, Guard Hua가 그랬어요
To protect your reputation.
귀하의 평판을 보호하기 위해.
Finally, the news of divorce
결국 이혼 소식이
Nothing is known.
알려진 바가 없습니다.
If someone saw it
누군가 그걸 봤다면
Tongues will wag.
혀가 흔들릴 것이다.
i know.
알아요.
Here it is.
여기있어.
OK. Let's drink together.
괜찮은. 같이 마시자.
Kill Jong Hee-woo to avenge our family!
우리 가족의 복수를 위해 종희우를 죽여라!
Protect us Lord!
주님을 보호하십시오!
Siu!
시우!
run!
달리다!
Let's go, girl! hurry!
가자, 아가씨! 서두르다!
Let's go, girl!
가자, 아가씨!
Let's go, Your Majesty!
가자, 전하!
???Chen...Shen...! ???let's go!
???첸...쉔...! ???갑시다!
Kian, let's go!
키안, 가자!
???Honey... ​​???Hurry! let's go!
???얘야... ​​???서둘러! 갑시다!
???hurry! ???Shen!
???서두르다! ???쉔!
mother...
어머니...
self...
자기...
???Go ahead and try it. ???What are you looking at?
???어서 해봐요. ???무엇을 보고 있나요?
???go! ???hurry!
???가다! ???서두르다!
???Halongzhou! ???go! fast!
???화룽저우! ???가다! 빠른!
let's go!
갑시다!
???Shen... ???Brother.
???쉔... ???형님.
wake up. fast!
일어나세요. 빠른!
???father. ???Qian...
???아버지. ???퀴안...
???Qian! ???father!
???퀴안! ???아버지!
go.
가다.
Go and protect Cuizhu.
가서 Cuizhu를 보호하세요.
Am I their target?
내가 그들의 표적인가요?
be careful!
조심해!
???My love... ???Shen!
???내 사랑... ???쉔!
hurry.
서두르다.
Kian!
키안!
sibling!
형제!
???Shen! ???Shen!
???쉔! ???쉔!
sibling.
형제.
Kian...
키안...
Did it hurt this much?
이만큼 아팠나요
When hit by an arrow?
화살을 맞았을 때?
Why did you take the hit for me?
왜 나를 위해 타격을 입었나요?
Qian, you also protect me from the Master.
Qian, 당신도 나를 마스터로부터 보호해 주네요
Didn't you?
그렇지 않았어?
I am... I am your older brother.
나는... 나는 당신의 형입니다.
How can I stay still and do nothing?
내가 어떻게 아무것도 하지 않고 가만히 있을 수 있겠는가?
When I see you in danger?
네가 위험에 처해 있는 걸 내가 봤을 때?
sibling...
형제...
Kian, don't be afraid...
키안, 두려워하지 마세요...
I'm fine.
난 괜찮아요.
I will protect you.
나는 너를 지켜 주겠어.
I'm with you. Hurt...
난 너랑 같이있어. 아픈...
I'll take you home
집에 데려다줄게
No, brother. It'll be okay.
아니, 형제님. 괜찮아 질거야.
I'll take you...
내가 데려다줄게...
Kian...
키안...
Kian!
키안!
Lord.
주님.
The reception hall was cleaned.
리셉션 홀이 깨끗해졌습니다.
Were the assassins caught?
암살자들은 잡혔나요?
There were many women in the hall.
홀에 여자가 많았어요
The guards made it difficult to catch them.
경비원이 그들을 잡기 어렵게 만들었습니다.
Most of the assassins fled.
대부분의 암살자들은 도망갔다
And some we caught
그리고 우리가 잡은 몇 마리
He committed suicide by taking poison.
독약을 먹고 자살했습니다.
They also took some girls with them
그들은 또한 몇몇 여자들을 데리고 갔어
I ran away like a hostage.
인질처럼 도망쳤습니다.
Who are they?
그들은 누구입니까?
Butler Lee's eldest daughter
버틀러 리의 큰 딸
Butler Wu's wife
버틀러 우의 아내
To the concubine...
첩에...
And the hostess.
그리고 여주인.
Magistrate Wang ordered the closure.
왕 치안판사는 폐쇄를 명령했다
And the Master is looking for them.
그리고 스승님은 그들을 찾고 계십니다.
Go and help the master.
가서 마스터를 도와주세요.
No, you can't, Lord.
아니요, 그럴 수 없습니다, 주님.
We are your personal security guards.
우리는 당신의 개인 경비원입니다.
We don't show up until we're needed.
우리는 필요할 때까지 나타나지 않습니다.
Otherwise we are like regular security guards.
그렇지 않으면 우리는 일반 경비원과 같습니다.
Saving comes first.
저장하는 것이 우선입니다.
???Lord! ???Yes, Lord.
???주님! ???예, 주님.
Let's go there. Go ahead and try it!
거기로 가자. 어서 해봐요!
There's nothing here, sir.
여기는 아무것도 없어요, 선생님.
???find. ???All right.
???찾다. ???알겠습니다.
Get out of the way.
비켜가세요.
No suspicious individuals were found, Master.
수상한 사람은 발견되지 않았습니다, 마스터.
???Continue searching. ???All right.
???계속 검색해 보세요. ???알겠습니다.
There's nothing here either, Master.
여기도 아무것도 없어요, 스승님.
???There’s nothing here either. ??? Please keep searching.
???여기에도 아무것도 없습니다. ??? 계속 검색해 보세요.
All right.
알겠습니다.
Master, there is no suspicious person nearby.
스승님, 근처에 수상한 사람은 없습니다.
Try a more thorough search.
더 철저하게 검색해 보세요.
All right.
알겠습니다.
Teacher, are you okay?
선생님, 괜찮으세요?
If you want to save Hwacheon and Muyao
화천과 무야오를 구하고 싶다면
Come alone to the cliffs of Eastern Town
이스턴 타운 절벽에 혼자 오세요
???Nanpung. ???I'm here.
???난펑. ???나 여기 있어.
Continue your search with the men.
남자들과 함께 수색을 계속하십시오.
Where are you going, teacher? I will go with you.
어디 가세요, 선생님? 나는 당신과 함께 갈 것이다.
no. Continue your search.
아니요. 검색을 계속하세요.
???Continue searching. ???All right.
???계속 검색해 보세요. ???알겠습니다.
Mu Yao.
무 야오.
You finally woke up.
당신은 마침내 일어났습니다.
who are you?
누구세요?
What good would it do to tie me up?
나를 묶는 게 무슨 소용이 있겠어?
What if you want to kill me?
나를 죽이고 싶다면?
It's not us who want to kill you.
당신을 죽이려는 것은 우리가 아닙니다.
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
Do you have a grudge against me?
나에게 원한이 있습니까?
You will find out later.
나중에 알게 될 것입니다.
How is my brother?
내 동생은 어때요?
Mu Yao, it finally happened.
Mu Yao, 마침내 일어났습니다.
Go ahead and try it. Can you become like a normal person?
어서 해봐요. 평범한 사람처럼 될 수 있나요?
look down. It's a cliff!
아래를보세요. 절벽이에요!
???Jong-ye-ran.???Stop it!
???종예란.???그만해!
Jong Ye-ran, how is my younger brother?
종예란, 내 동생은 잘 지내요?
What is Jong Ye like?
종예란 그는 어떤가요?
You came really quickly.
정말 빨리 오셨네요.
But you'd better step back.
하지만 넌 뒤로 물러나는 게 좋을 거야.
dare!
감히!
Do you know who you kidnapped?
당신이 납치한 사람이 누구인지 아시나요?
We did it. Of course we know.
우리는 해냈다. 물론 우리는 알고 있습니다.
I came alone.
나는 혼자 왔다.
Tell me please. What do you want?
말해 주세요. 당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
Jongye-ran, please choose one.
종예란, 하나 고르세요.
What nonsense are you talking about?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를하는거야?
What exactly do you want?
정확히 무엇을 원하시나요?
We don't want anything.
우리는 아무것도 원하지 않습니다.
We just want to see you and your family suffer.
우리는 단지 당신과 당신의 가족이 고통받는 것을 보고 싶을 뿐입니다.
Are you from the Ge family?
당신은 Ge 가족 출신입니까?
huh. you destroyed my family
응. 당신은 내 가족을 파괴했습니다
So you will definitely taste it today
그러니 오늘은 꼭 맛보게 될 거야
Losing someone you love!
사랑하는 사람을 잃는 것!
Stop!
멈추다!
You did it yourself.
당신은 스스로 그렇게했습니다.
And if you want revenge
그리고 복수하고 싶다면
Wouldn't it be easier to just kill Zong Yeran?
그냥 종예란을 죽이는 게 더 쉽지 않을까요?
Why did you kidnap us?
왜 우리를 납치했어요?
I heard you love your wife
당신이 아내를 사랑한다고 들었는데
And lots of concubines
그리고 첩을 아주 많이
Then it must be hard for you too.
그럼 너도 힘들겠구나
Make a choice, right?
선택을 하라고, 그렇죠?
yes. Their lives are now in your hands.
예. 그들의 삶은 이제 당신의 손에 달려 있습니다.
choose one
하나를 선택
And we're launching another one.
그리고 우리는 다른 하나를 출시할 것입니다.
But those who aren't chosen will become food
하지만 선택받지 못한 사람은 음식이 될 거야
For the fish in the lake.
호수의 물고기를 위해.
lake?
호수?
Which one would you choose?
당신은 어느 것을 선택하시겠습니까?
Why don't you choose anything?
아무것도 선택하지 그래?
Save yourself from self-blame
자기 비난으로부터 자신을 구하십시오
Just pick one.
하나만 골라서.
Who choreographed this?
이 안무를 맡은 사람은 누구인가요?
Did you just do this as a joke?
그냥 농담하려고 이런 짓을 한 거야?
Is this your first time being kidnapped?
납치는 처음이신가요?
Don't you know that you need to conduct a thorough search?
철저한 수색을 해야 한다는 걸 모르시나요?
Before taking someone hostage?
누군가를 인질로 잡기 전에?
You owe me something, Mu Yao.
나한테 빚진 게 있구나, 무야오.
???government! ???Qian!
???정부! ???퀴안!
Kian!
키안!
I never expected that one day I would be happy
언젠가는 내가 기뻐할 거라고는 전혀 예상하지 못했습니다
I have been exiled.
저는 추방당한 적이 있습니다.
Thanks to Yubae, I learned to swim.
유배님 덕분에 수영을 배웠습니다.
I can't stay here forever.
여기 계속 있을 수는 없어요.
The beasts will come out at night.
밤에는 짐승들이 나올 것이다.
When in Lingnan
링난에 있을 때
I've heard it once
한 번 들어본 적 있어요
That there are ordinary people
보통 사람이 있다는 것
Living in the upper class
상류층에 거주
What are you trying to prove?
무엇을 증명하려고 합니까?
you should have stayed on the cliff
넌 절벽에 머물렀어야 했어
And wait for Jong Ye-ran to make his choice.
그리고 종예란이 선택을 하길 기다립니다.
Maybe he was too nervous.
그 사람이 너무 긴장했을 수도 있어요
That person made the wrong choice
그 사람이 잘못된 선택을 했다고
And I wouldn't be the one he gave up on.
그리고 나는 그가 포기한 사람이 아닐 것입니다.
The terrain here is very rough.
여기 지형은 매우 험난합니다.
Even if Jong Ye-ran sends a man to look for me
종예란이 나를 찾으러 남자를 보내도
It won't arrive that fast.
그렇게 빨리 도착하지는 않을 거예요.
I suspect it's them.
그들이 아닐까 의심됩니다.
I finally found you.
드디어 당신을 찾았어요.
I'm so glad it's you!
당신이어서 정말 기뻐요!
I am really surprised now.
나는 지금 정말 놀랐다.
I didn't expect you to find me.
나는 당신이 나를 찾을 것이라고 기대하지 않았습니다.
I finally have someone by my side.
드디어 내 옆에 누군가가 생겼다.
I gave you this bracelet
내가 너한테 이 팔찌를 줬어
for your self defense
당신의 자기 방어를 위해
I'm not saying you should commit suicide.
당신이 자살하라는 것이 아닙니다.
Are you Hua Rongzhou?
Hua Rongzhou입니까?
No bone fractures.
뼈 골절이 없습니다.
I think I need some ointment.
연고가 필요할 것 같아요.
I will carry you on my back.
나는 당신을 내 등에 업고 갈 것입니다.
I can walk.
나는 걸을 수 있다.
We have walked a long distance.
우리는 먼 거리를 걸어왔습니다.
Why can't I see anyone around?
왜 주변에 아무도 보이지 않는 걸까요?
By the way, my brother...
그건 그렇고, 내 동생은...
Get on my back.
내 등에 올라 타세요.
I'm fine.
나는 괜찮아요.
hurry.
서두르다.
I'm not good at drinking.
나는 술을 잘 마시지 못한다.
I'm afraid that something embarrassing will happen later.
나중에 당황스러운 일을 당할까봐 두렵습니다.
Please take me downstairs.
나를 아래층으로 데려가 주세요.
Hostess, I know you can't hold your drink.
여주인, 당신은 술을 참을 수 없다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
???Go quickly. ???Then why did you do that...
???빨리 가세요. ???그럼 왜 그랬는데...
what's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
How did you know I was there?
내가 거기 있다는 걸 어떻게 알았나요?
What happened later?
나중에 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
How is my brother?
내 동생은 어때요?
After you and Mu-cheop were taken away
당신과 무첩이 끌려간 후
I followed Master to the top of the mountain.
나는 스승님을 따라 산 정상까지 올라갔습니다.
I don't really know what happened.
나는 무슨 일이 일어났는지 잘 모른다.
After the banquet is over
연회가 끝난 후
And Mr. Hwa’s condition.
그리고 화선생의 상태.
My sister will be okay, right?
내 동생은 괜찮을 거에요, 그렇죠?
I said I would follow my teacher.
스승님을 따른다고 했지
to the top of the mountain
산 정상으로
But I didn't see you.
하지만 나는 당신을 보지 못했습니다.
You don't pay any attention to me.
당신은 나에게 전혀 관심을 기울이지 않습니다.
I'm used to it.
나는 그것에 익숙하다.
No, that's not true.
아니요, 사실이 아닙니다.
I was dizzy from falling over a cliff.
절벽에 걸려서 어지러웠어
So I didn't notice you.
그래서 나는 당신을 눈치 채지 못했습니다.
Then do you remember...
그럼 기억나나요...
When did you first meet me?
나를 처음 만난 게 언제였나요?
Was it during ancestral rites?
조상제사 때였나요?
Just as I expected.
내가 예상했던대로.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Mistress, do you remember?
여주인님, 기억하시나요?
Did you ask my name four times?
내 이름을 네 번이나 물었나요?
No, I...
안돼, 난...
Why do I smell blood?
왜 피 냄새가 나나요?
Are you hurt?
상처받았나요?
It's just a small scratch.
작은 흠집일 뿐입니다.
scratch? Did you get hurt in the woods?
흠집? 숲속에서 다치셨나요?
Drop me off. I can walk alone.
내려 줘. 나는 혼자서 걸을 수 있다.
I have medicine.
나에겐 약이 있어요.
But how did you get here?
그런데 어떻게 여기까지 오셨나요?
But why were you alone?
그런데 왜 혼자였나요?
Who else did you expect to see?
또 누구를 볼 것으로 예상했나요?
Watch your tone!
말투를 조심하세요!
How dare you say that to me?
어떻게 감히 나한테 그런 말을 할 수 있어?
How rude! I am your mistress.
얼마나 무례한 일입니까! 나는 당신의 여주인입니다.
You're divorced now, right?
이제 이혼하셨군요, 그렇죠?
me...
나...
I'm older than you
난 너보다 나이가 많아
So you still have to respect me.
그러니 당신은 여전히 ​​나를 존중해야 합니다.
What should I call you...
널 뭐라고 불러야 될까...
After divorce?
이혼 후에?
That's right.
맞습니다.
When they leave Hwangcheong with me
그들이 나와 함께 황청을 떠날 때
Should they call me Miss?
그들이 나를 Miss라고 불러야 할까요?
But I wish they were free
하지만 나는 그들이 무료였으면 좋겠다
Live your own life.
자신만의 삶을 살아보세요.
Or has it never crossed your mind?
아니면 마음 속에 떠오르지 않았나요?
to take me with you
나를 당신과 함께 데려가려고
When leaving the species residence?
종 거주지를 떠날 때?
That's not true.
그건 사실이 아니야.
For Tsuiju
추이주를 위하여
I'll take you from your servant's residence.
종 거주지에서 데려다 드리겠습니다.
Why did it stop? Are you tired?
왜 멈췄나요? 너 피곤하니?
I said I could walk by myself.
나는 혼자서 걸을 수 있다고 말했다.
Get some rest. Hurt...
좀 쉬. 아픈...
Don't match me with Cuizhu again.
다시는 나를 Cuizhu와 일치시키지 마십시오.
You can play in the yard
마당에서 놀아도 돼
Or when you're attacked
아니면 공격을 받았을 때
I didn't want you to push me out to Cuizhu.
나는 당신이 나를 Cuizhu로 밀어내는 것을 원하지 않았습니다.
I told you to rescue Cui Ju. You heard me.
내가 추이주를 구출하라고 했어. 당신은 내 말을 들었습니다.
Then why didn't you do it...
그럼 왜 안 했어...
Because I like someone.
내가 누군가를 좋아하고 있기 때문이다.
Who is she?
그녀는 누구입니까?
Is that person in my house?
그 사람이 내 집에 있는 사람인가요?
yes.
예.
It's not kuijou. Are you Qianzhi?
쿠이주가 아닙니다. Qianzhi인가요?
???No ???Yinxing?
???아니요 ???Yinxing?
no.
아니요.
I named everyone in my house.
나는 내 집에 있는 모든 사람들의 이름을 지었습니다.
Don't say it's me.
나라고 말하지 마세요.
Say it.
말해보세요.
Did you say something?
뭔가 말했어?
Did you just say something?
방금 뭔가 말했나요?
you are a handsome man
당신은 잘 생긴 남자입니다
But to be clear:
하지만 분명히 말하자면
I am no longer interested in worldly pleasures
나는 더 이상 세상적인 즐거움에 관심이 없습니다
And I don't feel like falling in love
그리고 사랑에 빠질 기분도 없어
needless to mention
언급 할 필요없는
I don't like men younger than me.
나는 나보다 어린 남자를 좋아하지 않는다.
If there is someone like Huarongzhou
화룽저우 같은 사람이 있다면
In a past life
전생에
The person who protected me like his life depended on it.
자기 목숨이 달린 것처럼 나를 지켜준 사람
Had I made all those mistakes?
내가 그 모든 실수를 저지르지 않았을까?
Mistress, can I stop being your bodyguard?
여주인님, 경호원 그만둬도 될까요?
After I help you get what you want?
내가 당신이 원하는 것을 얻을 수 있도록 도와준 후에요?
Of course you can. You are a free man.
물론 넌 할 수있어. 당신은 자유인입니다.
But how do I know what I want?
그런데 내가 원하는 것이 무엇인지 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Why are you silent again?
왜 또 침묵하는 거야?
Say it.
말해보세요.
Isn't this my room in Qianzhi Hua Residence?
여기가 Qianzhi Hua Residence에 있는 내 방이 아닌가요?
Yes that's right.
예, 그렇습니다.
Hua Rongzhou brought me here?
Hua Rongzhou가 나를 여기로 데려왔다고?
yes.
예.
oh my god. I was confused for a while.
맙소사. 나는 한동안 당황했다.
I thought I was reborn.
나는 다시 태어났다고 생각했다.
By the way, how is my brother?
그런데 내 동생은 잘 지내요?
I believe he wasn't seriously hurt.
나는 그가 크게 다치지 않았다고 믿는다.
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
Why are you crying?
왜 울고 있어요?
Hostess, Master Hwayoung...
여주인, 화영 스승님...
government!
정부!
Stop.
멈추다.
Where is my brother?
내 동생은 어디 있지?
that...
그...
Bonus video
보너스 영상
tell the chef to get ready
요리사에게 준비하라고 말해요
Bamboo shoot soup for Qi Ruxin.
Qi Ruxin을 위한 죽순 수프.
It's her favorite dish.
그녀가 가장 좋아하는 요리입니다.
Come to think of it, that person didn't eat anything.
그러고 보니 그 사람은 아무것도 먹지 않았네요.
Yes, Your Majesty.
예, 전하.
Throw it away.
멀리 던져.
yes.
예.
What happened to that girl?
그 소녀에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?